# **ERIC QUELCH**

## </> FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

## **⊠** CONTACT

519-802-2824 quelchx@gmail.com London, Ontario



http://quelchx.com



http://github.com/quelchx



#### **EDUCATION**

Ontario Graduates Diploma Internet Applications & Web Development Fanshawe College Sept 2019 - April 2022 London, Ontario 3.23 GPA

## **PROFILE**

With a passion for tailored solutions, I'm seeking a position as a developer in a growing and thriving company. I have nearly four years of experience with HTML, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, and the fundamentals of Django, NodeJS and much more. I believe I have the ability to assist your company's IT team in developing and deploying web-based event and registration software tools.

#### **DEVELOPER SKILLS**

### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Experienced with Javascript, TypeScript, Python, Java, C# and PHP.

#### FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES

- Has extensive knowledge of React, NextJS, VueJS and NuxtJS for building component or template-based user interfaces.
- Able to design performant user interfaces using memoizing techniques to avoid unnecessary re-renders within components.
- Has experience designing custom hooks, higher-order functions and polymorphic components.
- Experienced with state management libraries such as Vuex, Redux or React Context.
- Capable of designing client-side, server-side or static generated web applications.
- Able to design RESTful APIs with Node.js and Express or Django with some experience using Ruby On Rails.
- Has experience with using Firebase's Firestore or MongoDB for creating NoSQL-based databases.
- Familiar with using Postgres or MySQL for applications with strong relational data structures.
- Capable of using Mongoose, TypeORM, and Prisma with TypeScript for creating object-relational model schemas on the backend.
- Is educated with WordPress, Strapi CMS, Nuxt Content and VuePress as content management services.
- Capable of using AJAX, Axios or other methods to send and receive data.
- Familiar with ThreeJS, React Framer Motion, React Spring and GSAP for creating additional animations for front-end applications.
- · Capable of styling user interfaces with CSS or Sass.
- Familiar with various styling libraries such as TailwindCSS, Bulma, Bootstrap, Material UI, and Chakra.

#### **SOFTWARE AND SERVICES**

- Familiar with Netlify, Vercel, Firebase and Heroku services to deploy various APIs or web applications.
- Possesses experience with Azure, AWS, and Linode to deploy various server-based applications.
- Capable of using Figma and Adobe Photoshop to design mock interfaces to utilize with designs.
- Has education with Git, GitHub, Docker, Bitbucket, Atlassian, and Jira for source management and project planning and control.

#### **RELATIVE EXPERIENCE**

#### JAVASCRIPT TUTOR, FANSHAWE COLLEGE; LONDON, ON -2020 - 2021

- Designed customized materials based on student's interests.
- Composed engaging lesson plans, allowing students to further their understanding of complex material, boosting motivation and session preparation for students.
- Collaborated with students to complete homework assignments, identify lagging skills and assisted with correcting weaknesses.
- Planned sessions and allowed time to strengthen weak subjects and build skills.
- Provided early intervention assistance to struggling students.

#### OTHER EXPERIENCE

#### TECHNICIAN SUPERVISOR, KAL TIRE; LONDON, ON -2019 - 2021

- Managed, trained and supervised a team of 5 to 8 junior technicians.
- Performed inspections of all vehicle types within MTO guidelines.
- Diagnosed issues and performed proper tasks to fix occurring problems.
- Maintained fleet vehicles in good working order in accordance with OEM preventive and corrective maintenance schedules.
- Serviced tires, repaired tire injuries within specific guidelines, changed or topped off fluids and completed various maintenance when required.

#### ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

CASHIER, THE BEER STORE; BRANTFORD, ON -2018 - 2019 TECHNICIAN. CAINSVILLE TIRE: BRANTFORD, ON -2014 - 2018

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

## Vue Writer

- Over 7000 downloads
- Used on over 20 websites
- http://npmjs.com/package/vue-writer

## **AOS Vue**

- Has over 2000 downloads
- Used on over 20 websites
- http://npmjs.com/package/aos-vue

## Mdote

- Markdown-based note editor.
- http://mdote.netlify.app